This Koshinage hip throw is going to be from an overhead strike, Shomen uchi.
Right here.
This is a very dynamic throw.
As Daniel's coming in, I need to close the gap to him.
And I use his cut, as he's cutting down, as part of the technique.
It's very difficult just to heave him off the ground, so I want him to do most of the work.
Because you're going to come in, and enter the gap, close to him, and cut him down over my back.
I'm here, I've loaded him in my hips here.
Literally load him up onto my body, and I would use my hip flip motion to turn him over.
As you notice it's pretty easy for me to turn around with Daniel, because he's on my hips.
He's not on my upper back, he's not twisted.
He's centered on my back.
So Daniel comes in, I'm here, to the side, catch that leg, and load him up on your hips.
Let's do that one more time.
I'm here, protect myself, load him on the hips, load him up, just like this.
Let's go ahead and do the throw now.
Here.
And we'll do that one more time.
And that is Koshinage, or hip throw, from an overhead, Shomen uchi, strike.